# THEODORE MAUBEC

CIVIL ENGINEER

## **Personal Profile**

I am a confident, forward-thinking person who has worked domestically and internationally in diverse, fast-paced working environments. I have held various posts of responsibility, thus demonstrating my strong work ethic, excellent time management and the ability to communicate effectively and openly with others.

# **Honors & Achievements**

- Masters in Civil Engineering (2:1)
- · Personal Pilots License
- Diploma in Percussion
- RYA First Aider
- Emergency First at Work
- · Fire Safety Training

### **Skills**

- Operational Management
- Teamwork and Leadership
- Time Management
- Adaptability and Flexibility
- Strategic and Analytical Thinking
- Fully Competent with MS Office
- High Mathematical AptitudeComputer Aided Drawing (CAD)

- Personal Interests

   Piano and acoustic gigs
- Travelling, hiking, surfing, climbing and squash
- Photography
- Cooking
- Yoga
- Golf (handicap of 5)

# **Academic Background**

# **Elizabeth College**

Secondary School (2005-2012)

- A-levels in Mathematics (B), Physics (B), Biology (B) and Photography (A\*)
- School Photography Prize Winner
- Golf Team Captain

# **Work Experience**

# Site Engineer/Manager

JW Rihoy & Son Ltd · July 2020 - December 2021

- Initially involved in a multi-structure £35 million project as a setting out
  engineer and quickly developed a broader range of duties including site
  quality control, the implementation and installation of multiple radon gas
  mitigation systems, environmental matters regarding the site
  remediation strategy, and a managerial role in a £10 million office block
  included within the whole project.
- Oversaw the completion of a waterproof basement concrete box, the
  erection and completion of the superstructure on a new £8 million, high
  profile site with multiple logistical challenges whilst simultaneously
  carrying out the role of site engineer and site manager.

# **Site Engineer**

Stefanutti Stocks · Dec 2017 - Dec 2018

- Operationally managed the construction of a 5-star hotel for the King of Swaziland; overseeing the quality control of the 1.6 billion Rand project whilst performing the duties of site engineer and site agent.
- Duties included distributing information, maintaining verbal and written communication between the project team, consultants and subcontractors: essential to running of the site.
- Promoting and implementing various environmental recycling and reusability techniques on site to reduce impact and increase sustainable practices.
- Enforced high standards of HSW as a base requirement on site to encourage innovative thinking to minimise near misses, delays and adverse environmental effects.

#### Instructor

Outdoor Guernsey · June 2016 - Oct 2019

- Leading and supervising both groups and individuals in various outdoor pursuits. Teaching relevant skills and ensuring their safety throughout whilst working in a collaborative manner.
- Relaying informative knowledge on the diversity and conservation of fauna and flora in the local ecosystem.
- First point of contact with the public. Any feedback, positive or negative
  was communicated directly to the customers, providing an opportunity for
  repeat business in the future.

### **University of Exeter**

Masters in Civil Engineering (2013-2017)

- 2nd Class Degree with Honours
- Academic Excellence in geotechnical engineering, environmental studies, water distribution and management, financial management and sustainability within engineering
- Projects specialising in sustainability including; developing alternative methods of water filtration in third world countries and investigating the use of natural ventilation in modern buildings instead of mechanical HVAC systems.

# **Contact Details**

07860 837079